Guide to the Andrew Dickson White papers, 1832-1919.
White, Andrew Dickson papers, 1832-1919
- Series II. Manuscripts, Documents, and Items
  - Report on the Provision for Higher Instruction in Subjects Bearing Directly upon Public Affairs, 1878-1887 (Box 169, Folder 5-6)
  - Report on Instruction in Social and Political Science, April 16, 1879 (Box 169, Folder 7)
  - "My Visit to Wittenberg" manuscript by White, May 17, 1880 (Box 169, Folder 8)
  - Speech as banquet in New York, October 4, 1881 (Box 169, Folder 9)
  - Speech: Resolutions establishing fellowships, scholarships, and a loan fund, and setting apart $130,000 for that purpose, 1883 (Box 169, Folder 10)
  - Brief History of Cornell University and its Prospects, dictated to Ellen Coit Brown, ca. 1883 (Box 169, Folder 11)
  - Reply to attacks by New York alumni, April 30, 1883 (Box 169, Folder 12)
  - Message of the 19th century to the 20th, June 26, 1883 (Box 169, Folder 13-14)
  - Speech at Cleveland on the Education of the Freedmen, October 26, 1883 (Box 169, Folder 15)
  - Cornell University scholarships and fellowships, 1884 (Box 169, Folder 16-17)
  - Speech: Historical Instruction at Cornell University, August 30, 1884 (Box 169, Folder 18)
  - In defense of H.W. Sage, September 2, 1884 (Box 169, Folder 19)
  - A reply to provision for religious instruction at Cornell University, December 13, 1884 (Box 169, Folder 20)
  - "Co-education at Cornell" manuscript by White, January 26, 1885 (Box 169, Folder 21)
  - Choice of a successor to presidency of Cornell University, 1885 (Box 169, Folder 22-23)
  - Notes on the history of Cornell University (Box 169, Folder 24)
  - Draft of talk on college fraternities, 1887 (Box 169, Folder 25)
  - Speech: On the Founding of Cornell, 1887 (Box 170, Folder 1-6)
  - Fortnightly Club address, Buffalo, New York, January 16, 1890 (Box 170, Folder 7)
  - "How to Choose a College" manuscript by White, 1890 (Box 170, Folder 8)
  - "A University at Washington" manuscript by White, 1890 (Box 170, Folder 9)
  - "Training for Farmers" manuscript by White, 1890 (Box 170, Folder 10)
  - "Future of the American Colleges and Universities" manuscript by White, 1891 (Box 170, Folder 11)
  - "Democracy and Education" manuscript by White, July 7, 1892 (Box 170, Folder 12-13)
  - Dartmouth College speech, February 4, 1896 (Box 170, Folder 14)
  - Hearing before the Senate Committee on the establishment of the University of the United States, February 10, 1896 (Box 170, Folder 15)
  - "Evolution vs. Revolution" manuscript by White, June 9, 1896 (Box 170, Folder 16-18)
  - Address presenting portraits, February 22, 1897 (Box 170, Folder 19)
  - Speech at Oxford, October 2, 1902 (Box 170, Folder 20)
  - Address at laying of the corner stone of Goldwin Smith Hall, October 19, 1904 (Box 171, Folder 1)
  - Address to Cornell Alumni at NYC, February 25, 1905 (Box 171, Folder 2)
  - John Morris obituary notice, 1905 (Box 171, Folder 3)
  - Ground-breaking at NY State Agricultural College Building address, 1905 (Box 171, Folder 4)
  - Pioneers and Pioneer work in Central New York (Box 171, Folder 5)
  - "Prospects of Freedom for Russia" manuscript by White, January 11, 1906 (Box 171, Folder 6)
  - Speech at George Washington University, March 14, 1906 (Box 171, Folder 7)
  - Address before Association for the Advancement of Science, June 29, 1906 (Box 171, Folder 8)
  - "Samuel Pierpont Langley" manuscript by White, December 3, 1906 (Box 171, Folder 9)
  - Notes on manuscripts, 1907-1908 (Box 171, Folder 10)
  - Speech at 80th Birthday of Hiram Corson, November 6, 1908 (Box 171, Folder 11)
  - "The Cornell University Bells" in the Cornell Era, December, 1908 (Box 171, Folder 12)
  - Historical Association Address, 1908 (Box 171, Folder 13)
  - Speech to alumni at Buffalo, February 20, 1909 (Box 171, Folder 14)
  - Talk on courtesy and manners, June, 1909 (Box 171, Folder 15)
  - Presentation speech to dean TF Crane, June, 1909 (Box 171, Folder 16)
  - Sigma Phi Convention speech, June 18, 1909 (Box 171, Folder 17)
  - Presentation of Loving Cup to Professor Hart, November 2, 1909 (Box 171, Folder 18)
  - Lecture on Bismark, July 13, 1909 (Box 171, Folder 19)
  - Statement for the trustees on Professor Goldwin Smith, July 7, 1910 (Box 171, Folder 20)
  - Democrats and Republicans at Cornell, 1910 (Box 171, Folder 21)
  - "The Work of Benjamin Hale" manuscript by White, June 15, 1911 (Box 171, Folder 22)
  - Speech to Alumni at Syracuse, May 29, 1912 (Box 171, Folder 23)
  - Two addresses at University of Michigan, June 26, 1912 (Box 171, Folder 24)
  - "Letter of an Octogenarian to Cornell Students" manuscript by White, November 7, 1912 (Box 171, Folder 25)
  - "Memories of Athletics" manuscript by White, June, 1913 (Box 171, Folder 26)
  - Address at Alpha Sigma Phi dinner, September 22, 1913 (Box 171, Folder 27)
  - "Dean Bailey from the Point of View of a Trustee" manuscript by White, November, 1913 (Box 171, Folder 28)
  - Introduction General Report of class Secretaties, 1913 (Box 171, Folder 29)
  - Speech: The Beginning of Sibley College at Cornell, June, 1915 (Box 171, Folder 30)
  - Cemetery dedication at Fayetteville, October, 1864 (Box 171, Folder 31)
  - Speech at welcome of 185th regiment, 1865 (Box 171, Folder 31)
  - Sketch of address at the 50th anniversary of Cortland Academy, 1870 (Box 171, Folder 31)
  - Address at the funeral of Samuel Joseph May, July 6, 1871 (Box 171, Folder 31)
  - Speech at the Tyndall banquet, New York, February 4, 1873 (Box 171, Folder 31)
  - Eulogy of Edward Lasker (Box 171, Folder 31)
  - Silliman Address, Yale, June 24, 1889 (Box 171, Folder 32)
  - Remarks at the unveiling of memorials to Mrs. Ezra Cornell, June 15, 1892 (Box 171, Folder 32)
  - Address at 50th anniversary of Onondaga County Orphan Asylum, 1875 (Box 171, Folder 33)
  - Frederick William Holls memorial address, Columbia University, October 22, 1903 (Box 171, Folder 33)
  - Address to Business Men's Association of Ithaca (Box 171, Folder 33)
  - John Hay address, December 2, 1906 (Box 171, Folder 34)
  - Speech at Homer Academy, June 26, 1907 (Box 171, Folder 34)
  - Speech at the "Daddy" George banquet, February 8, 1908 (Box 171, Folder 34)
  - Remarks at the unveiling of a memorial tablet to Hiram Bingham Jr and Charles Harding, Yale., June 29, 1909 (Box 171, Folder 34)
  - Speech at a dinner in White's honor in Washington DC., April 3, 1911 (Box 171, Folder 34)
  - Remarks at the memorial service for Stewart L. Woodford, February 23, 1913 (Box 171, Folder 35)
  - Charles Loring Elliott and his relation to American art, October 11, 1913 (Box 171, Folder 35)
  - Talk before the Cortland County Society, January 22, 1914 (Box 171, Folder 35)
  - Remarks at the funeral of the reverend Herzer, October 16, 1914 (Box 171, Folder 35)
  - Speeches - Political (Box 172)
  - Speeches - Political (Box 173)
  - Reviews of Autobiography (Box 174, Folder 1-4)
  - "Plans for McGraw-Fiske Library", 1896 (Box 174, Folder 5)
  - Study for Auditorium College of Musical Culture and School of Architecture (Box 174, Folder 6-7)
  - Undated Cornell University and White financial papers (Box 174, Folder 8)
  - Undated Cornell University and miscellaneous buildings and grounds (Box 174, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous papers, fragments (Box 174, Folder 10)
  - "A Plea for the Present Age" manuscript by White, ca. 1848 (Box 175, Folder 1)
  - College Essays by White (Box 175, Folder 2)
    On Drama, Translation of Eneid, Timothy Olbuck, Prometheus, Yankee Letters, Our Brood of Great Men, and miscellaneous
  - College Essays by White, on Yale Lit. Prize (Box 175, Folder 3)
  - Latin translations, mathematics paper, 1847-1848 (Box 175, Folder 4-6)
  - "Should Infidel Publications be Suppressed?" manuscript by White, ca. 1848 (Box 175, Folder 7)
  - "The Crusades" essay by White, March 12, 1849 (Box 175, Folder 8)
  - Outline of a General History Course (Box 175, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous outlines of lecture series (Box 175, Folder 10)
  - Notes and fragments of lecture preparations (Box 175, Folder 11)
  - Lecture: French Institutions before the Revolution: Part III, the Church (Box 175, Folder 12)
  - "Eulogy of Edward Lasker" manuscript by White, January 10, 1884 (Box 175, Folder 13)
  - Original draft of the Silliman address, June 24, 1884 (Box 175, Folder 14)
  - Address at Onondaga Orphan Asylum, 1895 (Box 175, Folder 15-16)
  - Address at graveside of Samuel J. May, July 6, 1871 (Box 176, Folder 1)
  - Co-education clippings by White, 1872 (Box 176, Folder 2)
  - "Industrial Education in the United States" manuscript by White, May 1, 1874 (Box 176, Folder 3-4)
  - "Relation of the National State Governments to Advanced Education" manuscript by White, August 5, 1874 (Box 176, Folder 5)
  - "How shall our universities and colleges help the policies of the nation?" notes by White, 1875 (Box 176, Folder 6)
  - Notes on the faculties of History, Political Science, Economy, and Law in European Universities, 1878 (Box 176, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript on Military Question, July, 1879 (Box 176, Folder 8)
  - Notes on various subjects, mainly democracy and education, 1880 (Box 176, Folder 9)
  - Autographs of the Class of 1861 at University of Michigan (Box 176, Folder 10)
  - List of Diplomatic Corps at Berlin, 1880 (Box 176, Folder 11)
  - Spoils System manuscript by White, February, 1882 (Box 176, Folder 12-13)
  - "The New Germany" manuscript by White, 1882 (Box 176, Folder 14-19)
  - Message of the 19th century to the 20th, first draft, 1883 (Box 176, Folder 20-21)
  - Speech at the unveiling of the portrait of Senator Morrill, first draft, June 20, 1883 (Box 176, Folder 22)
  - Blaine campaign clippings, 1884 (Box 176, Folder 23)
  - Annual talk, 1884 (Box 176, Folder 24)
  - Psi Upsilon speech, 1884 (Box 176, Folder 25)
  - Remarks at the Conference of College Presidents, 1884 (Box 176, Folder 26)
  - "On Studies in General History and the History Civilization" manuscript by White, September 9, 1884 (Box 176, Folder 27-28)
  - "The Influence of German Thought upon the United States" manuscripts and drafts by White, October, 1884 (Box 176, Folder 29-31)
  - Drafts of Introduction to Brun and Chanels "French Revolution", 1887? (Box 177, Folder 1)
  - White Historical Library bulletin, July, 1887 (Box 177, Folder 2)
  - Draft of speech at Corner Stone of Crouse College, ca. June 7, 1888 (Box 177, Folder 3)
  - Catalogue of the President White Library- Protestant Reformation, 1889 (Box 177, Folder 4)
  - Draft of Speech at exhibit of F. B. Carpenter picture, 1891-1892 (Box 177, Folder 5)
  - Documents on Administration of Cities, 1892 (Box 177, Folder 6)
  - "The Murder Problem in the United States", August 15, 1892 (Box 177, Folder 7-8)
  - Notes on Civil Service Reform, April, 1892 (Box 177, Folder 9)
  - Sketch of Address on Municipal Reform, April, 1892 (Box 177, Folder 10)
  - Liste du Corps Diplomatique, St. Petersbourg, 1893 (Box 177, Folder 11)
  - Lists and correspondence on furniture purchased in St. Petersburg, September, 1894 (Box 177, Folder 12)
  - "Commence and Diplomacy" manuscript by White, January 18, 1896 (Box 177, Folder 13)
  - Farewell speech drafts to German Americans, May 22, 1897 (Box 177, Folder 14)
  - Baden-Furniture, sale of furniture to minister of Baden, correspondence, documents, fire insurance, 1897 (Box 177, Folder 15)
  - Horace White letter of acceptance newspaper clipping, 1898 (Box 177, Folder 16)
  - Clipping from Troy NY Daily Times, White on his work at Cornell, 1898 (Box 177, Folder 17)
  - Speech at Leipzig on the President of the United States, clippings from the German press, July 4, 1898 (Box 177, Folder 18)
  - Clippings on White in German, July, 1898 (Box 177, Folder 19)
  - "Walks and Talks Count Tolstoy" manuscript by White, February 2, 1899 (Box 177, Folder 20)
  - Translation of article from "Nord Deutcher Allgemeine Zeitung" on the Hague Peace Conference, August 5, 1899 (Box 177, Folder 21)
  - Report of the President on the Needs of Cornell University, Schurmann to Starr Murphy, March 4, 1901 (Box 177, Folder 22)
  - Hotel Bills: Rome, Zurich, Naples, Berlin, San Remo, Venice, 1902 (Box 177, Folder 23)
  - Address at Leipzig on William McKinley, two drafts, July 4, 1902 (Box 177, Folder 24)
  - Articles in leading German newspapers on White's retirement as American ambassador, November, 1902 (Box 177, Folder 25)
  - Notes on Egypt, 1891 (Box 177, Folder 26)
  - "Der Tag" newspaper with picture of White dinner in honor of Rhodes, June 26, 1902 (Box 178, Folder 1)
  - "Frederick William Holls", drafts and letter to Monroe Smith, October 22, 1903 (Box 178, Folder 2)
  - "Bishop Davis at Yale, by His Chum", written by White, with obituaries, November 20, 1905 (Box 178, Folder 3)
  - "John Hay" manuscript by White, December 2, 1906 (Box 178, Folder 4)
  - "Evolution vs. Revolution in Politics" manuscript by White, June 1906 (Box 178, Folder 5)
  - "Courts of Conciliation" by Nicolay Grevstad, 1904-1906 (Box 178, Folder 6)
  - "Prospects of Freedom for Russia" drafts, notes, January, 1906 (Box 178, Folder 7)
  - "Democracy and Education" manuscript by White, May 11, 1906 (Box 178, Folder 8)
  - "Samuel Pierpont Langley" first draft, December 3, 1906 (Box 178, Folder 9)
  - Address on Ezra Cornell given at the Centennial Celebration, Ithaca, April 26, 1907 (Box 178, Folder 10)
  - Speech at Homer Academy, June 26, 1907 (Box 178, Folder 11)
  - 40th anniversary celebration address, "Old and New University Problems", June 17, 1908 (Box 178, Folder 12)
  - "Abraham Lincoln" manuscript by white, two drafts and an outline, February 12, 1909 (Box 178, Folder 13)
  - Speech before alumni at Buffalo, with newspaper remarks, February 20, 1909 (Box 178, Folder 14)
  - Remarks on the Unveiling of a Memorial Tablet to Hiram Bingham Jr. and Charles Harding, by White, June 29, 1909 (Box 178, Folder 15)
  - "The Hague Conference" manuscript by White, December 24, 1909 (Box 178, Folder 16)
  - "Crime in Christendom", alternate title "The Problem of High Crime in the United States" by White, January 23, 1910 (Box 178, Folder 17)
  - Goldwin smith manuscript by White, three drafts, December 2, 1910 (Box 178, Folder 18)
  - Clippings on co-education at Cornell, 1910 (Box 178, Folder 19)
  - Notes on High Crime in the United States, January 1911 (Box 178, Folder 20-21)
  - University at Washington clippings and notes, April, 1911 (Box 178, Folder 22)
  - "The Work of Benjamin Hale" manuscript by White, June 15, 1911 (Box 178, Folder 23)
  - "The United States and Russia" manuscript by White, December 6, 1911 (Box 178, Folder 24)
  - "The Abrogation of the Russian Treaty" speech by White, December, 1911 (Box 178, Folder 25)
  - Materials on Benjamin Hale and talks on Technical Schools, 1911 (Box 178, Folder 26)
  - Clipping of White's views on students smoking, 1911 (Box 178, Folder 27)
  - Draft of remarks at Author's Club, 1911 (Box 178, Folder 29)
  - Cornell Reorganization pamphlets, 1911-1914 (Box 178, Folder 30)
  - Speech at dinner of the Syracuse Alumni, May 29, 1912 (Box 178, Folder 31)
  - Address on laying the corner stone of the Ithaca City Hospital, July 28, 1912 (Box 178, Folder 32)
  - Extension of President's House, 1911, 1912 (Box 179)
  - Fiat Money in France notes, drafts, galleys, letters (Box 180)
  - 80th Birthday Congratulations (Box 181)
  - Book and Bowl Club talk, January 15, 1913 (Box 182, Folder 1)
  - Address at the Waldorf-Astoria Dinner, January 18, 1913 (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Woodford Commemoration address, February 23, 1913 (Box 182, Folder 3)
  - Evolution vs. Revolution in Politics" manuscript by White, May 29, 1913 (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Alpha Sigma Phi convention banquet address, September 22, 1913 (Box 182, Folder 5)
  - Panama-Pacific Exposition manuscript, correspondence, notes, October, 1913 (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Birthday greetings and telegrams, November, 1913-1914 (Box 182, Folder 7-9)
  - Cornell Reorganization manuscripts and correspondence, 1913-1914 (Box 182, Folder 10)
  - Talk before Cortland County People, January 22, 1914 (Box 182, Folder 11-12)
  - Adrmiral Diederich's Incident, correspondence and clippings, February, 1914 (Box 182, Folder 13)
  - Beaham Charges vs. Cornell Trustees correspondence, March, 1914 (Box 182, Folder 14)
  - Third Hague Peace Conference correspondence, February, 1914 (Box 182, Folder 15)
  - Acquisition of Bailey Hall organ, correspondence and bills, April-November, 1914 (Box 182, Folder 16)
  - "Books and Reading" manuscript by White, notes, March, 1915 (Box 182, Folder 17-19)
  - Speech at Alumni dinner, June, 1915 (Box 182, Folder 20)
  - New York Constitution printed material, 1915 (Box 182, Folder 24)
  - Investments, 1915 (Box 182, Folder 25-26)
  - Biographical sketch for Knckerbocker Pub. Co., February, 1916 (Box 182, Folder 27)
  - Cornell University Inscriptions: White Statue and other memorabilia (Box 183, Folder 1)
  - White Statue clippings, 1915 (Box 183, Folder 2)
  - Regrets to invitations to the unveiling of statue of AD White, 1915 (Box 183, Folder 3-4)
  - Cardiff Giant, 1869 (Box 183, Folder 5)
  - Cardiff Giant reminiscences of AD White (Box 183, Folder 6)
  - Cardiff Giant: "The American Goliath", 1869 (Box 183, Folder 7)
  - Onondaga Giant, 1869 (Box 183, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper clippings on Cardiff Giant, 1869 (Box 183, Folder 9)
  - Cardiff Giant humbug, 1870 (Box 183, Folder 10)
  - The Galaxy- Cardiff Giant, 1872 (Box 183, Folder 11)
  - Cardiff Giant (Box 183, Folder 12)
  - Points in American experience bearing upon Mr. Carnegie's gift to Scotland (Box 183, Folder 13)
  - "Socialism" rough draft, never developed (Box 183, Folder 14)
  - European History Lectures (Box 184)
  - Seven Great Statesmen (Box 185)
  - Notes on Jefferson (Box 186)
  - Misc. Mss. not all dated (Box 187)
  - Warfare of Science (Box 188)
  - Warfare of Science (Box 189)
  - Warfare of Science (Box 190)
  - Warfare of Science (Box 191)
  - Warfare of Science (Box 192)
  - Warfare of Science (Box 193)
  - Warfare of Science (Box 194)
  - Warfare of Science (Box 195)
  - History of the Warfare of Science (2 ann. sets), 1897, 1907 (Box 196)
  - Warfare and Science Mss. & Articles, 1887-1908 (Box 197)
  - Published Articles - Not all dated (Box 198)
  - Published Articles - Not all dated (Box 199)
  - Bibliography (Box 200)
  - Bibliography (Box 201)
  - Notes on Immigration and Crime (Box 202)
  - Notes on Immigration and Crime (Box 203)
  - Notes on International Law (Box 204)
  - Old diplomatic matters, Berlin (part of the autobiography) (Box 205, Folder 1)
  - Poem by CF Allen, read on the occasion of the presentation of the bust of ADW by alumni, June, 1887 (Box 205, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Santo Domingo (Box 205, Folder 3)
  - Representative in Congress (Box 205, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Thiers' government (Box 205, Folder 5)
  - Municipal reform notes (Box 205, Folder 6)
  - Notes on AD White by Theodore Munger (Box 205, Folder 7)
  - Legislative acts in NY, notes on early study at Cornell (Box 205, Folder 8)
  - Opinion of Judge Boardman on Constitutionality of Cornell University Title (Box 205, Folder 9)
  - Materials on business difficulties of Professor Evans (Box 205, Folder 10)
  - Notes on the castle of La Punta Pozzo di Borgo (Box 205, Folder 11)
  - Notes on attendance of Sage Chapel, schedules of Cornell faculty salaries (Box 205, Folder 12)
  - Reports of the Smithsonian Institution, 1913, 1914, 1916 (Box 205, Folder 13)
  - Notes on Marie Antoinette (Box 205, Folder 14)
  - Notes on history (Box 205, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 205, Folder 16)
  - German clippings on American Universities (Box 205, Folder 17)
  - Furniture, old bills, insurance, etc. (Box 205, Folder 18)
  - Furniture: Berlin (Box 205, Folder 19-22)
  - Messages of the President of the United States...on the subject of the Mexican War., 1848 (Box 206)
  - Catalogue of the porcelain collected by A.D. White 1879-1903, housed in the old President's house. Prepared by Mrs. Beatrice Magill Robinson, 1914 (Box 206)
  - Two Judges note books, International exhibition, 1876 (Box 206)
  - Account book with portrait photograph of unknown individual and letter in Italian (Box 206)
  - Record of employees, 1886-1888 (Box 206)
  - Notebook with names, possibly attendance records, from University of Michigan, 1858-1859 (Box 206)
  - Subscriptions to Pedestal for Statue of Liberty, 1884 (Box 206)
  - Addresses of Americans specially introduced, October-November, 1902 (Box 206)
  - Exercises in the use of French, 1854-1856 (Box 206)
  - Account book of A.D. White's cook (R. Flatow), 1879-1881 (Box 206)
  - Catalogue of cases 1-4 of Italian Gems, bought in Berlin, 1881 (Box 206)
  - Calling Cards and Invitations (Box 209)
  - Newspaper Clippings (4 scrapbooks ) (Box 210)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 211)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 212)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 213)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Loose & Misc.) (Box 214)
  - News Clippings, Photos and Diary (Box 215)
  - White Family Genealogy (Yale Class Book, etc.) (Box 218)
  - Berlin Financial Statements (Box 219)
  - Financial Records (Box 220)
  - Financial Records (Box 221)
  - Financial, 1860-1900 (Box 222)
  - Financial, 1901-1914 (Box 223)
  - Financial and Legal, 1915-1918 (Box 224)
  - Cornell Directory, handwritten with notes by White. (Box 207)
  - A.D. White address book (Box 207)
  - Medals awarded to A.D. White (Box 208)
  - A.D. White letterbook, 1897-1901 (Box 207)
    Relates to controversy over leasing and decorating of apartment in Berlin and inventory of household possessions. Also, letter to Charles Francis on involvement in founding the University.
  - Diary Transcripts Vols. 1-18, 1853-1879 (Box 226)
  - Diary Transcripts Vols. 19-29, 1880-1891 (Box 227)
  - Diary Transcripts Vols. 30-42, 1892-1904 (Box 228)
  - Diary Transcripts Vols. 43-55, 1905-1918 (Box 229)
  - Manuscript materials on Santo Domingo, 1871 (Box 232, Folder 1)
  - Lecture notes in hard covers, 1859, 1876 (Box 234)
    Including: Erasmus, The New Diffusion of Thought, The New German Empire, Canisius and the Counter Reformation in Germany, Metternich, German Revolution, Reformation, Revival of Art and Learning, and others
  - Newspapers (Box 230, Folder 27)
    "The Daily Sun" January 8, 1907; "Syracuse Daily Journal" November 15, 1882; "New York Times" March 16, 1890; "Cornell Summer Daily" July 5, 1913; "The World" New York, February 18, 1912.
  - White's galley proofs of a piece on the nebular hypothesis. A note says "never published" (Box 230, Folder 30)
  - Lecture on the Causes of the French Revolution, 1888 (Box 230, Folder 31)
  - Printed lectures on history, 1860, 1883 (Box 230, Folder 32-33)
  - Notes of Reference on canal to Pedro Miguel., 1907 (Box 231, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper clippings about AD White (Box 240, Folder 1-3)
  - Embroidered book cover (Box 240)
  - Frederick White's diary, 1875 (Box 240)
  - A.D. White's Last Will and Testament, including drafts (Box 237)
- Series III. Diplomatic Documents
  - Appointment as member of the Venezuela Boundary Commission, January 4, 1896 (Box 242, Folder 5)
    Signed by Richard Olney and Grover Cleveland
  - Appointment of White as Minister to Germany, April 2, 1879 (Box 242, Folder 5)
    Signed by Rutherford B. Hates and William Evarts
- Series IV. Diplomas, Degrees, and Certificates
  - Honorary Doctorate from University of Jena (Map-case 3)
  - Diplome commemoratif offert a Monsieur Andrew D. White Commissaire honoraire des Etats-Unis, Paris Le ler Janvier, 1880 (Map-case 1)
  - Certificate of appointment as ambassador extraordinary and plenipotentiary to Germany, 1897 (Box 243, Folder 2)
  - Labels, "Mr. Andrew Dickson White, Ambassador of the United States of America", Undated (Box 243, Folder 2)
  - Certificate of honorary membership in Prussian Scientific Academy, 1900 (Box 243, Folder 2)